you know I had prepared a message for
tonight or is it this morning
and after I had finished
there's this message that I'd shared
some time back but kept getting
impressed in my spirit that I should
come and share it tonight so I talked to
my advisors at home asking them which of
this do you think I should preach and
there was no consensus so when we got
here and everybody kept talking about
the same thing the same thing the same
thing I realized God maybe wanting us to
share on this subject the message is
simply entitled stop struggling stop
struggling
pastor ang that is a title of our
message and pasta Mugabe has almost
preached all of it stop struggling isn't
it that's what he was telling us just to
enjoy a rest just to enjoy a rest our
text is found in Genesis chapter 32 from
verse number one to verse 32 as you can
see that is a very long text so we will
not read it but we'll read it as we go
along different sections that we'll be
seeing but to just help us understand
what is about the stories that at a time
when Jacob had just managed to corn lab
on his uncle who was also his
father-in-law of a great amount of
wealth
Jacob had escaped the pass route of
Lebanon
because Leben was following him because
one of Jacob's wives who was Leben's
daughter had stolen Laban's gods now if
your gods can be stolen you need to
change your gods now at this very point
where we pick the story jacob is running
away from Leben but ahead of him there
is the prospect of meeting with his
brother Esau in so as you know he had
also conned Esau of his birthright
so on the one hand he has conned his
uncle and is now running away on the
other side he had called his brother and
he is going to meet him this is what
some people say is caught between the
rock and a hard place and so Jacob does
not know what he should do and from this
story I want us to see the futility of
struggling with life this is why our
team last year was not by might not by
power but by my spirit says the Lord so
the first thing we see is a futility of
living without God all living without
the favor of God Jacob was so afraid of
this encounter with his brother that
when you read a story he gets into a
very detailed program of trying to
appease his brother
so that he can escape he saw rough so in
Genesis chapter 32 verse number 5 we
find him asking for eso's favor the
Bible says now I am sending this message
to my Lord that I may find favor in your
eyes he's told his his servants to go
and tell ezel but I am sending this
message that I may find favor in your
eyes in verse number 7 chapter 32 he
divided his people and his wealth into
two groups and two portions the Bible
says in great fear and distress Jacob
divided the people who are with him into
two groups and the flocks and herds and
camels as well they say you don't put
your eggs in one basket and so because
he's going to meet his brother who he
doesn't know how he will meet him or
will treat him Jacob takes caution and
says let me divide my people into two if
one is attacked at least I'll escape
with the other one so he divided his
people into two it was number 11 he
prays to God even after doing all those
things that God may save him he says in
verse 11 save me I pray from the hand of
my brother Esau for I am afraid he will
come and attack me and also the mothers
with their children this man is terribly
afraid of his brother and so after he
has done all those strategic actions he
now goes back to God and prays that God
may save him
vast number 13 to 15 he tries to bribe
his own his brother
the Bible says from what he had with him
he selected a gift for his brother Esau
now you know bribes are not called
bribes
they're called gifts isn't it
so he took something small as we do in
Kenya something small so from what he
had with him he selected a gift for his
brother Esau now listen to this small
gift verse 14
two hundred female goats twenty male
goats two hundred years twenty Rams
thirty female camels with a young 40
cows ten bulls 20 female donkeys and ten
male donkey something small to appease
his brother so that he does not attack
him vast number seventeen and eighteen
he now tries to flutter his brother in
verse 17 the Bible says he instructed
the one in the lead now those are his
servants that when they get to the
brother when my brother is o meets you
and asks to whom do you belong and where
are you going and who owns all these
animals in front of you then you are to
say what are they to say they belong to
you a servant Jacob they are a gift sent
to my lord
Esau and he is coming behind us since
when did Jacob become the servant of its
own since when is Dedes or become the
Lord
of Jacob but you know when you want good
things what do you do this is how you
behave my lord yes sir yes madam isn't
it because you want favor here is a
perfect example of the futility of
operating outside of God's favour
here is a man who the Bible says was
loved of God even before he was born now
some of us you may only have known of
God's love after you are born but for
Easter for Jacob it is said he was
chosen of God before he was born in
Romans chapter 9 verses 10 to 13 the
Bible says not only that but Rebecca's
children had one and the same father our
Father Isaac yet before the twins were
born or had done anything good or bad in
order that God's purpose in election
might stand not by works but by him who
calls she was told the older will serve
the younger
just as if it's written Jacob I loved
but Esau I hated this Jacob whom God
loves whom God loved before he was born
while he was in this mother's womb God
had a special love for Jacob this is not
the general love where we say for God so
loved the world not includes you and I
this is a special love this is what we
call favored are we together this is
special favor that God has extended to
Jacob so this man was not an ordinary
man like you and I the
man was chosen by God God loved Esau
very especially very specifically this
is what we would call in ordinary
language a man born with a silver spoon
in his mouth he was not only chosen but
loved by the Heavenly Father well before
he knew anything about what love is this
man was so favored by God that even in
this text as he was running away from
Leben the Bible says in Genesis chapter
32 verse 1 and to Jacob also went on his
way and the angels of God met him when
Jacob said saw them he said this is the
camp of God so he named that place maja
9 this man as he is running away from
his uncle God sends angels ahead of him
what manner of favor what manner of love
is this but for some strange reason here
is a contradiction what pastor Andy
would call the paradox
Jacob believed that if he was to succeed
in life he had to fight for it Jacob
believed that the only way to succeed in
life is to hustle
Jacob would have proudly described
himself as a-- he did not know and
recognize that actually he was a special
boy he was a special child and so here
he is struggling with life hustling
struggling he was a sufferer
and so right from birth
Jacob is Sephora struggler hustla that
is how he ended up grabbing the heel of
his brother before they were born the
man started hustling in the womb hoping
that he could of attack his brother when
that did not work and the brother came
out fast he had not given up because his
dreams were valid
so Jacob is not given up you have come
out first but somehow I am still going
to be the firstborn now when a man has
been born second born how can he be
first born but as for Jacob that was
still possible so he is thinking how do
I become a fast ball why did Jacob be
want become a fast ball because in the
Jewish culture the firstborn always got
a double portion when the inheritance
was being divided if you are two
brothers and your father has nine acres
of land what he does is he divides it
into three portions so three acres three
acres three acres isn't it then he gives
the firstborn six acres and the
second-born three acres that is how it
used to happen and Jacob being a lover
of life and property and wealth realize
that I am NOT going to be satisfied with
reoccurs I must get a way of getting the
six acres which is normally preserved
for the
so Jacob plans on how he's going to work
out something so that he becomes a
firstborn
other than killing his brother so he did
a trick and he ended up becoming the
firstborn and when things turned out
difficult he ran to Laban's house when
he got to Robin's house he met his match
because lemon was another con man laughs
and his uncle was another in fact I was
telling some people I have reason to
believe that this con man ship came from
the mother's side because you remember
for them to call for him to call his
brother Esau who organized the mother is
the mother who organized out they could
call their father when Jacob was saying
now but if father fathers didn't know
leave this to me I'm going to sort it
out I know the man and the way to a
man's heart through his stomach I'm
going to prepare him the food like they
like and he likes when he has eaten he
will give you the blessing so the
mother's brother is called who Lebon so
when Jacob ends happen happens plays he
finds that now this is a home of con man
ship
a Haslam is a fellow fellow Haslam and
so they are fighting each other over
ship over goods you know until finally
Leben even cons him out of a wife
remember he loves Rachel who was the
firstborn Rachel yes who is the second
born and he stole you have to work seven
years to get this one so mine faithfully
works seven years after he has worked
seven years he's given his wife but he
didn't remove the veil before the
wedding so when he woke up in the
morning he finds dessert Rachel it is
lair he has been conned Jacob was trying
to con a con man and he met his match
and so imagine after he has discovered
this instead of the uncle apologizing
what does the uncle say if you want it's
Rachel work another another seven years
con men have no sympathies no they said
don't say oh no no I'm sorry you know if
this was a mistake I actually thought I
was giving you Rachel but somehow it
ended up say no if you love Rachel
another seven years but Jacob loved
Rachel so much that he worked another
seven years this is now the life of this
man who was loved of God but now a time
of reckoning comes for Jacob and he has
nowhere to run and so we find Jacob in
deep desperation
in verse number 22 of chapter 32 the
Bible records that night Jacob got up
and took his two wives his two maid
servants and his eleven sons and crossed
the ford of jack de baak after he had
sent them across the stream he sent over
all his possession
so Jacob was left alone now the prospect
of meeting his brother gets this man
into a state of depression he has done
all that a man can do he has sent his
people he has sent his gifts and
everything but he still feels I am not
safe he has prayed he is still not safe
so finally he takes his wife he takes
his children he goes out and goes by the
stream and he is left alone
time of reflection the picture here is
our man who is deeply distressed his
schemes could not give him peace of mind
his ideas could not secure him the
comfort of the soul he had come to the
his wits end and his scheming could not
save him the man now just wanted time
alone did whoa it all the time of rest
time just rest he shut himself in it is
important to realize that our struggles
will never give us peace
some of us are here you skim you do all
manner of things but they won't get you
very far don't get you very far
it is important sometimes just stop and
reflect like Jacob
so Jacob stops and reflects shuts
himself in a time of Prayer and while he
is in that time of Prayer the struggler
meets another struggle and in the
darkness of the night the Bible says in
verse 24
so Jacob was left alone and a man
wrestled with him till daybreak can
imagine you are sleeping in the darkness
of the night somebody comes and begins
to struggle and fight with you and they
wrestle and they wrestle and of course
Jacob was used to wrestling he wrestled
all his life he had wrestled with every
kind of thing so later Jacob discovers
that the money was wrestling with wars
who God God himself so when Deborah came
and the man wanted to leave Jacob did
not did only what Jacob can do he hangs
on to this God and vast r-25 says when
the man saw that he could not overpower
him he touched the socket of Jacob's hip
so that his hip was wrenched as he
wrestled with a man
Jacob is a wrestler Jacob is a struggler
Jacob is a hustla Jacob is a sufferer
Jacob is all those things
he's so prevailed even upon God that God
had to break the rules of the game in
order to get Jacobs hip he dislocated
Jacob's hip I'm sure many of us have
questions as to what exactly is going on
here can a man really win a wrestling
match against God of course not
but for Jacob everything had to be
fruitful even blessings I will not let
you go until how many of you do that I
know preachers have told you wrestle for
your blessing using this text you don't
have to wrestle God is a good god
Alleluia God is your father God has good
plans for you why do you have to wrestle
but for Jacob everything was good
through sweat
so even blessings he says I will not let
you go until you bless me and so if it
when he could not let God go God touch
the socket of his hip one thing I had
said he went away leaping but blessed
limping but blessed
what a man this is for Jacob the kingdom
of God suffers violence and the violent
take it by force
and so the man obliged and asked him
what is your name Jacob he answered then
the man said in verse 28 your name will
no longer be Jacob but Israel because
your struggled with God and with men and
you have overcome God deals directly
with jacob's problem the spirit of
struggling is faced squarely and dealt
with his prayer is answered in a manner
that he will never forget his name is
changed and his blessing
is bestowed upon him Jacob goes away
limping but blessed
we come to chapter 47 of Genesis and now
Jacob is at the end of his life he has
struggled with his brother from the womb
he has struggled with his father and
called the father he has struggled with
his uncle and called the uncle he has
struggled with God and got blessing from
him he has struggled he has struggled
his struggle this man only knew the life
of struggling he believed that god helps
those who help themselves
isn't it you know that Scripture god
helps those who help you unless I fight
unless I struggle I will not get it now
in Genesis chapter 47 this now Jacob is
an old man his son Joseph is in Egypt
and this famine in the land and so
Joseph reveals himself to his brothers
who had come to look for food in Egypt
finally he calls the whole family to
come to Egypt and the whole family comes
Jacob included together with his whole
household when they get into Egypt
Joseph is prime minister to Pharaoh and
as would happen in any setting when your
parents come you go to into your
children your family comes you go to
introduce to your boss
so Jacob Joseph takes Jacob to Pharaoh
to introduce him to Pharaoh and so they
taxi takes Jacob to Pharaoh and leaves
the two old men
to fellowship now listen to what happens
in verse number eight in Chapter 47
pharaoh asked him how old are you and
Jacob said to Pharaoh the years of my
pilgrimage are a hundred and thirty now
listen to what he says next my years
have been few and difficult I they do
not equal to the years of the pilgrimage
of my father's the man is a hundred and
thirty years I can confidently say that
none of us will get to that age because
the life expectancy of Kenyans is half
of that actually less than half but even
if God gives you grace to get there to
130 that is a long life for a man whom
God loved from the womb what should have
been his testimony my life has been nice
and beautiful I have lived in the
goodness of the Lord pasta but what does
jacob say the years of my pilgrimage are
a hundred and thirty my years have been
few and difficult brothers and sisters
that is a testimony of stragglers
it is true it is the testimony of
strugglers men and women who believe
that unless I fight unless I skim unless
I do things it will not happen and so
every day a of waking time they are
everything is about scheming
it's about conning is about doing this
and about doing that and fighting with
your brother and fighting with your
sister and trying this and trying the
other everything has to be fought for
when you are old age comes you look back
and say my life has been shot and
difficult my life has been shot and
difficult past and I read for us some to
read for us 70 73 you look at people who
seem to be doing very well they seem to
be doing very well when they are given a
government job the first thing they want
to do is how to empty the coffers of
government into their coffers because
they believe that unless I do this my
life cannot be okay I was speaking to
engineers they had invited me to the
Institute of a Kenyan Institute of
Engineers or is it Institute of
Engineers of Koenig whatever it is but
all the engineers invited me for to
speak at their annual dinner and they
asked me to speak on professional ethics
and so I talked about many things that
the challenges we face in this country
because engineers are simply not doing
their job the roads that just
get worn out before the contractors
finished at the other end bridges that
collapse buildings that collapse on
people and all those kinds of things
they are done by engineers
I give them example Lenin a road right
here when it was recapitalize final
injury if you may know
soon after the contractor left there
were two huge holes that developed there
one time I almost got an accident
because in the process of somebody tried
to avoid that all found me on my side
and we almost we missed narrowly why
because an engineer did not take time to
sort out and make sure that the road is
done according to standard hard wings
codec was stomached before the
contractor finished at the other end
this side was done was finished worn out
completely
it was supervised by an engineer I'm
just talking about one profession what
could have happened is that this
engineer is eating with a contractor
because they believe unless I get this I
cannot make it in life the reason I gave
you that illustration or that story is
that when I finished I said any
questions so we've had a question time
one of the engineers lifted up is unless
a bishop if we did what we asked what
you are saying
we would die poor
so this is the Jacob spirit that
believes that unless I struggle unless I
struggle unless I struggle I will die
poor so they're scheming they are
planning they are scheming they are
planning against their own brothers
they are scorning them out of the land
that you are the inheritance that you
are father left for you you are calling
your own father Jacob conned his own
father saying I am in so when he knows
he is Jacob the father touches him I
said yeah the hunt looked feels like is
so but the voice sounds like Jacob is
because I've eaten a grasshopper
so they can't even their fathers he
calls his own uncle and finally he is
been struggling with God how much can a
monster ago xuan but they're people who
believe in that now compare Jacob
compared jack up with his father who was
Jacob's father Isaac you remember when
we were talking about and blocking the
ancient wells some of you are here and
Jacob not a yucca but Isaac said about
because there was drought in the land he
set about to unblock the wells that his
father Abraham had dug many years ago
and he wouldn't block a well and when
the water came out the people around him
would come and beat his servants out of
that well and said this is was our well
this was our well instead of Isaac
fighting Isaac would leave that well for
them and he would go and dig another one
then they would come again and say no no
no this is our well this our forefathers
well Jack Isaac lives that well for them
and goes and digs another one until he
dug a well where they no longer
contended with him listen to this
in Genesis chapter 26 verse 19 the Bible
says Isaac's servants dug in the valley
and discovered a wealth of fresh water
there but the herdsmen of Gera quarreled
with Isaac's herdsmen and said the water
is ours so he named the well ESSEC
because they disputed with him
then they dug another well but they
quarrel over that one also so he named
it sit now I think he wanted to say
fitna but it says it now he moved on
from there and dug another well and no
one quarreled over it he named it
Rehoboth saying now the Lord has given
us room and will flourish in the light
Isaac did not believe in struggling he
did not struggle over wells because he
knew that every good and perfect gift
comes from the father above and indeed
when he left his destiny in God's hands
the Lord appeared to him that night the
Bible says in Genesis chapter 26 verse
23 from here there he went up to
Beersheba that night the Lord appeared
to him and said I am the God of your
father Abraham do not be afraid for I am
with you I will bless you and will
increase the number of your descendants
for the sake of my servant Abraham the
Bible says I will not had not have time
to go on if you read that story and we
read it when we doing and blocking
radiant wealth that God so blessed Isaac
that his hurts his camels and everything
they were so blessed that the people his
own neighbors were jealous and envious
of him and said this man is truly
blessed
because he had discovered how to relax
and enjoy the blessing of God without
struggling
I believe Jacobs story speaks to us
about our own pilgrimage with God in our
pursuit of our own desires it is
possible to live a life that is nothing
else but a struggle a struggle to
achieve our selfish ambitions we are
ready to use every possible means to
attain the success with desperately
aspire for and so our lives are one
struggle after another with anyone who
stands in our way for us like Jacob we
have struggled with brothers we
struggled with relatives we are
struggling with business partners we are
struggling with employers we are
struggling with spouses we are
struggling with our children we are
struggling and struggling and struggling
there was a lady that I know born-again
Christian
she was so desperate for promotion
desperate for promotion at a place of
work and so he went to this group who
say if you want promotion this is what
you do here is anointing oil go very
early in the morning before your boss
comes to work and anoint his desk anoint
his sit and pray over it anoint his
office so that when it comes to that
office he will be favorable to you
sounds very good but what is the
difference between that and witchcraft
what is the different brethren just
because you're calling Jesus does not
make it any different from witchcraft
so this dear sister went and anointed
the place and anointed the place by the
time we are talking with her in my
office she was frustrated she was like
Jacob my life has been short and
difficult because this thing had not
worked I have not worked so I don't know
my dear sister that is witchcraft
whoever told you that it has misled you
just trust in God for promotion does not
come from the east or from the West
promotion comes from above from the
Father that's why a promotion control so
this means of carrying Erie in your
pocket called anointing oil yeah the
people of the world were Carrie Reese's
isn't it but the people of God Carrie
what what is the difference what is the
difference here the same I went for an
international global Christian meeting
and we were given
a small cross to carry in the pockets as
you talk with people you can be touching
it
brothers and sisters you may laugh but
we have brought witchcraft in God's
house we are not different from Jacobs
wife who stole the gods of his of her
father and now the father is chasing
some of us have stolen the gods of our
fathers and brought them into God's
house and your father is chasing all
these struggles we are trying very hard
to make it in life we somehow believe
that unless we do something our lives
will end up in misery and so we struggle
on the fact is that no matter how great
a wrestler you are one of these days you
are going to run out of breath and run
out of ideas
do you see Jacob now alone he has run
the Lebon is behind Esau is ahead he has
run out of ideas
he finally goes to God and say God save
me from my brother save me from my
brother save me from my brother
and when God appears to him what does he
do he fights with God
my sister my brother we are in 2020
leave the struggles of last years where
they belong
in your family you may have been
struggling your father may have been a
struggling your parents may have been
struggling your brothers have struggled
that's how they have made it in life but
as for you come to God and say my father
my father my sister you preach my
message Jehoshaphat looks at the army
and says Lord we have nowhere to go only
you are our Savior and instead of
putting together an army he puts
together a worship team why because he
knows that only God can save us if you
are going to survive in this year of
2020 it does not matter how many
promises we give you it does not matter
I know pastors given us we are getting
get millions I notice that when you
mentioned middle week week left my
friend will be three well let me tell
you you will not get that million
through hustling you will not get that
million through con Manship you will not
get that million and even if you get one
day you will sit down and say now what
have I achieved in my life what is there
to see for all the struggles I have
Solomon
pastor mentioned him goes to God and
asks for wisdom and God blesses him with
great great wisdom as Solomon sets out
in his wisdom to do a research to find
out what as human being man gained for
all his Labor's in life because when he
looked at everything his problem
statement those of you do research his
problem statement is meaningless
meaningless everything is meaningless
vanity vanity everything is vanity he
has worked as such the problem stated
the research question what does a person
gain out of his hard work in the short
time that God has given him in this life
so Solomon set about to do his research
and I tell you he does research on
everything everything he says I looked
at poverty and I looked at riches I
looked at foolishness and I looked at
wisdom I looked at he did everything the
one area he did very well was on women
and he said I married many of them but
my mind was still with me he says
himself how he is mine stayed with him
with 700 women I do not know one is
difficult enough
my sister you know we love each other
[Laughter]
how do you handle Savannah but he was
doing research I was doing research it
is true go and read Ecclesiastes is that
research it's a research report and in
Chapter number 12 of Ecclesiastes
he gives the findings and he says here
is the conclusion of the matter after he
has done his analysis he has looked at
the results he says here is the
conclusion of the matter what was the
conclusion of the matter fear God
no base commandments if you want your
life to be okay the greatest the wisest
man of all did research on everything
and he says finally what matters fear
God and obey His commandments your life
will be all right you'll be sorted out
he did research on youth he said young
man
enjoy yourself but remember all these
things you will be brought to judgment
he did brothers and sisters fighting
fighting fighting will not help you
struggling struggling struggling will
not help you what you need is the favor
of God
the favor of God upon you Jacob had a
son as I close now Oh Jacob had a son
and his son was called Joseph Joseph did
not follow the ways of his father
Joseph was not a struggler Joseph did
not fight with life Joseph did not
scheme Joseph lived in the favor of God
every place he went he was favored favor
he had favor in the home the parents
somehow loved him when they went out
they brought him good things until the
brothers were jealous when he was taken
as a slave sold in the marketplace
favored do you know that kind of people
would buy a slave he would end up in a
wrong place but God's hand was upon him
he is bought by Potiphar and he ends up
in royalty that is favor people are
employed but some people are employed we
are not all employed the same way isn't
it
some are employed and others are
employed favor
so Jacob and Joseph is being they are
being sold with other slaves in the
marketplace but because the hand of God
is upon him he is bought by Potiphar
when he goes into Potiphar's house he
doesn't struggle now Lord where how can
I will I had loved you so much how did
you you gave me these dreams now see
where I've ended up no no just obsess
about his work and he works so well the
Bible says that with Joseph in charge
what if I did not bother with anything
other than the food that he ate
works very hard because he knows the
hand of God is upon him when a woman now
comes favor he's favored even with looks
the man was built up and handsome like I
am so so God favors him but now do you
know when you're favored some people
want to abuse your your favor so this
woman sees him and wants him to sleep
with her but Jacob no Joseph knows I am
operating under God's favor the moment I
will move outside of God's favour that
favor is gone I've become a struggler so
as this woman is saying sleep with me
come to bed with me sleep with me come
to bed with me Joseph says hey how can I
do such a thing and sin against my God
because he knows that the things that he
is enjoying as a result of God's favor
therefore he cannot abuse it so if they
when the woman tried to force her him
who does he do he runs off I would
rather lose my job than lose my god
that's Joseph's reasoning he runs off
the man ends up in prison in prison is
not struggling he is not a struggler he
serves because he knows even in prison
God is with me and so he is serving
there with all his heart until he gets a
promotion in prison he's a chief
prisoner
brothers and sisters even if you're poor
be among the chief of the poor don't
just say Oh homie you know now we we
elope why we elope wanna look nice like
a woman until when people see you they
think hey you know good but they don't
know that there's even no point in you
are in your pocket but you look so good
that you get promotion so he gets into
prison but because the car he knows the
hand of God is upon him Joseph does not
struggle with life he simply does his
work and once again the warden leaves
the work of the prisoners to him in the
process people are coming to consult he
becomes a consultant in prison people
are coming to consult him I had a dream
and this is this what was happening what
do you think was this this was a party I
think this is what it is the man he's
sorted another one comes I had a dream
what do you think this means is this the
man is also sorted that is how he ends
up in the palace because one of the guys
he sorted in prison goes to the palace
and the Pharaoh has a dream and he says
I know a man when we were in prison he
sorted me out I think he can also sort
you out the man is brought out of prison
and put brought before Pharaoh he
interprets the dream fast he tells
Pharaoh Pharaoh says I have asked the
magicians and I have as the Chan
enchanters and they are not able to
interpret Joseph makes it very clear
Noma can interpret your dream only God
hallelujah only God
and this is what God has revealed to you
and interprets Pharaoh's dreams after
that Pharisees who else but you he's
given promotion what am I saying
brothers you don't have to struggle in
life you don't have to struggle with the
life
stop being a hustla stop being a
struggler stop being of Sephora because
you are loved of God one text that my
wife loves a lot is found in officience
and it says that God so loved us we
while we were lost in sin without hope
Christ who is rich in mercy came and
brought us out and is now seated us in
the heavenly places my friend you are no
ordinary person we are a royal
priesthood a holy nation a people
belonging to God why should you struggle
with life if you have a resolution you
want to make in 2020 make this
resolution stop chuckling I'm not going
to struggle
I'm not going to struggle
in the short light time that have lived
my life in this world and is a very
short life
seriously brethren I can tell you my
life has been short and favored it has
been favored God by his own grace
somehow has blessed my life and I have
come now as I see my life going towards
a close because I'm now going to as a
close I have come to realize you don't
have to struggle just live life don't
struggle just live life God is on your
side if something is difficult people
are struggling over your well whatever
in denial
Quanah Nannini God will give you rebels
a place of rest
well that is flowing and you will be
okay
but this thing of fighting with everyone
some of us are killing one another over
quota a cadet your father left to your
brother God will give you 20 acres a man
who pangas are being drawn over water
eka which is the only inheritance that
your father left behind and you are
killing one another over it let it go
some of you are struggling with your
process you are struggling with your
colleagues you are struggling with
everyone and less scheming and we are
new seeing people you know the part I
didn't tell you when Joseph tried to
skim the backfired
after he had interpreted the dream he
told the guy now when you go there
please remember me two years the man
forgot he could do you know God does
those things for us so that you know
that my help comes from the Lord you go
to your uncle and your uncle can't even
see you because that is where you had
anchored your hope your uncle can't even
see you so now you are lost you are lost
but when you look to the Lord did I tell
you that story I am a storyteller past I
should stop now yes
let me tell this story and then I finish
I have told it on this pulpit before
there's a day I was going to do
something in town and I was looking for
parking and this Sun was hot it was one
of those cars that have no air
conditioner
I was roasting in that car
and went round and round and round
looking for packing finally I remembered
my wife works at stunt stunt yet I was
this constant son bunkhouse and they
have packing in the basement so I
thought let me call my wife she'll give
me a packing at the basement so I called
her no answer I was so frustrated I went
round round I couldn't find Pocky
finally like Jacob I was so frustrated I
am so thirsty I am so roasted it was in
the middle of the day I just in my
frustration I said God please give me
packing it was desperate frustration
before I finished that one sentence
prayer the car right in front of me
moved out just moved out I packed in
there I start from a minute I said Lord
how foolish how foolish why did I pray
Aliyah
why had I not praise alia I wouldn't
have been so roasted in this car i
repented before the Lord because I had
been struggling going round and round I
went to City Market I went to where I
went the whole CBD I drove all around
there was no
sometimes I see a parking like there
somebody come so in my total desperation
of frustration I just say lord please
give me parking and the guy in front of
me
pulls out and I just go there brothers
and sisters as how is sometimes struggle
we think that in our own wisdom we can
sort it out we think that in our own
energy we can't
it is not by might it is not by power it
is by the Spirit of God just say lord
please sort me out and he will sort you
out
hallelujah this message was to wind up
our previous theme not by might not by
power but by the Spirit of the Lord this
Sunday I will now be bringing the
message I should have preached this
evening so please come and join me and
it is entitled maintaining a 20/20
vision I'm sure you don't want to miss
let's let us pray together
[Music]